Finding Aid for Department of Internal Medicine (University of Michigan) records, 1931-1997
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Department of Internal Medicine (University of Michigan) records
1931-1997
1971-1996
University of Michigan. Department of Internal Medicine.
861041 Bimu C46 2
Unit of the University of Michigan Medical School, records include minutes of meetings of senior staff members; also other materials concerning intern and residency training, and scattered correspondence and lecture notes; includes chairman's files of William N. Kelley, divisional files and administrative records.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
27.3 linear feet in 28 boxes
The record group (donor # 7292 ) has been received in several accessions, beginning in 1986.
Periodic additions to the records are expected.
The Department of Internal Medicine records are open for research except for certain records restricted by statute or university policy. Restricted material includes personnel-related files, including search, review, promotion, and tenure files; student educational records; client/patient records; and records of executive officers of the university.
The Department of Internal Medicine record group includes restricted material in the following categories:
Personnel Related Records -- Boxes 16-21
Student Academic Records -- Boxes 16-21
Patient/Client Records -- Boxes 16-21
The Department of Internal Medicine of the University of Michigan Medical School had its origins in 1848 when Abram Sager was appointed professor of Theory and Practice of Medicine. The department included, at various stages, divisions and studies of pathology, pediatrics and other medical disciplines in the fledgling field of internal medicine. The department was officially given the name of Department of Internal Medicine in 1908.
Dr. Cyrus C. Sturgis was named the first chair of the Department of Internal Medicine in 1928; he served at this post until his retirement in 1959. Sturgis divided the department into four general medical services: medical outpatient service, private medical service, tuberculosis service and a diabetic outpatient service. Over time the department grew and changed to parallel the changes in medical research and science. Dr. William D. Robinson succeeded Dr. Sturgis as chair of the department in 1959. He was replaced by Dr. William N. Kelly in 1971. (Dr. Robinson's personal papers are also located at the Bentley Historical Library.)
Under Dr. Kelly's leadership, the department's budget grew from $2 million to $39 million as he strove to make it one of the leading departments in the country. Divisions were added and restructured as Kelly worked to develop and strengthen clinical research and new multi-disciplinary centers. He also sought to improve interdepartmental cooperation and collaboration. Dr. Kelly left the department in 1990. He was replaced by Dr. Tadataka Yamada, who served until 1996. Yamada was followed by H. David Humes.
As of 1993, 14 divisions comprise the department: Allergy, Cardiology, Endocrinology and Metabolism, Gastroentology, General Medicine, Geriatric Medicine, Hematology and Oncology, Hypertension, Infectious Diseases, Molecular Genetics, Neurology, Nuclear Medicine, Pulmonary, and Rheumatology.
For more information, see the department's web page at: http://www.med.umich.edu/intmed/.
The records of the department have arrived in three separate accessions in 1986 (box 1), 1992 (boxes 2-21), and 1998 (boxes 22-28).
The 1992 accession of the records of the Department of Internal Medicine are primarily from the years when William Kelly served as chair (1971-1990). The accession is divided into five series: Division Files, Topical Files, Meeting Minutes, Chairman's Files, and Pollard Medical Research Institute.
The 1998 accession contains the files of Chris Durovich, the Chief Administrator of the Department of Internal Medicine and covers the period from 1990 to 1996. As one would expect given this origin, these materials are focused more on the administration of the department than on its medical mission. The many topical files relating to managed care and organizational restructuring (such as the Cost Effectiveness Program (CEP), Redesign Coordinating Group, and Structure Work Group) reveal the many pressures on the department during this period. Durovich was also active in many inter and intradepartmental committees and workgroups, including the Clinical Departmental Administrators and the DAAD (Division Administrators and Directors); he also attended the Division Chiefs Meetings. This accession is divided into two series: Topical Files and Financial Files.
The record group includes a significant amount of closed records, mostly personnel and student records. The closed files are listed in their logical order in the collection, but at the time of processing were physically removed to separate boxes of closed files. Some files now open are still housed in the closed boxes. Consult the reference staff to gain access to these files.
Subjects:
Internal medicine--Michigan.; University of Michigan. Medical School.; University of Michigan. Division of Cardiology.; University of Michigan. Division of Geriatrics.; Interns (Medicine)--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Residents (Medicine)--Michigan--Ann Arbor.
Contributors:
Kelley, William N. 1939-
- Early Administrative Records, 1931-1959
  This linear foot of the Department of Internal Medicine records consists of two series. The first series, Early Administrative Records, contains information dating from 1931 to 1959, including notes from discussion groups regarding intern and residency programs, medical school teaching, and patient and outpatient care, as well as correspondence and lecture notes, copies of major addresses given before Internal Medicine staff and students, personal notes and lecture outlines by Dr. Cyrus C. Sturgis, Chief of Medical Service. This series also contains the Precedent Book for Instructors in Charge of Interns, developed by Dr. Sturgis in 1931, which contains information regarding the specific duties of interns and the manner in which their work was to be supervised.
  - Discussion Groups, 1958-1959 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, 1944-1956 (Box 1)
  - Precedent Book for Instructors in Charge of Interns, June 30, 1931 (Box 1)
- Meeting Minutes, 1944-1973
  The second series contains Meeting Minutes from November 1944 to December 1973 arranged chronologically.
  - 1944-1973
    - November 1944-December 1949 (Box 1)
    - January 1950-December 1952 (Box 1)
    - July 1956-December 1958 (Box 1)
    - January 1959-December 1961 (Box 1)
    - January 1962-June 1963 (Box 1)
    - July 1963-December 1964 (Box 1)
    - January 1965-December 1965 (Box 1)
    - January 1966-December 1967 (Box 1)
    - January 1968-December 1969 (Box 1)
    - January 1970-June 1971 (Box 1)
    - July 1971-December 1973 (Box 1)
- Division Files, 1962-1987
  The Division Files (4.25 linear feet) series, arranged alphabetically by division name, documents development of and changes in the fourteen divisions of the Department of Internal Medicine. Planning, recruitment, research and the establishment of various study and treatment centers, such as the Diabetes Research and Training Center in the division of Endocrinology and Metabolism, are documented through correspondence, memos and reports.
  - Allergy Division, 1975-1984
    - General, 1975-1982; 3 folders (Box 2)
    - Allergy Fellows, 1976-1977 (Box 2)
    - Allergy Recruiting, 1975-1984; 10 folders
      - 1975-1976 (Box 16)
      - 1976-1977, 2 folders (Box 16)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 16)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 16)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 16)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 16)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 16)
      - 1982-1983 (Box 16)
      - 1983-1984 (Box 16)
  - Annual Reports, 1975-1979 (Box 2)
  - Assistant Director for Finance (search for), 1981-1982 (Box 16)
    [PR RESTRICTED until July 1 2082 ]
  - Awards, 1979-1982
    - Jerome W. Conn, 1979-1982
      - 1979-1980 (Box 16)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 16)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 16)
    - Brighton Health Center, 1980-1982; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Cardiology Division, 1962-1984
    - General, 1975-1984; 4 folders (Box 2)
    - Care Unit, 1962-1978 (Box 2)
    - Interdepartmental Relations, 1984 (Box 2)
    - Recruitment, 1975-1984; 8 folders (Box 2)
      - 1975-1977 (Box 2)
      - 1975-1978 (Box 2)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 2)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 16)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 16)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 16)
      - 1982-1983 (Box 16)
      - 1983-1984 (Box 16)
    - Sports Medicine Center, 1982-1984; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Clinical Medicine Review Subcommittee, 1975-1976 (Box 2)
  - Clinical Sciences, Introduction to, 1974-1984; 6 folders (Box 2)
  - Committees, 1977-1984; 6 folders (Box 2)
  - Consulting and Teaching Fees, 1977-1978 (Box 3)
  - Contributors, 1976-1982; 6 folders (Box 3)
  - Critical Care Medicine, 1979-1982; 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Departmental Office Positions, Affirmative Action Information, 1978-1979 (Box 16)
  - Endocrinology and Metabolism Division, 1975-1985
    - General, 1975-1984; 8 folders (Box 3)
    - Budgetary Matters, 1978-1979 (Box 3)
    - Development Funds (allotments and expenditures), 1979-1980 (Box 3)
    - Diabetes Research and Training Center, 1976-1984; 8 folders (Box 3)
    - Equipment, 1983-1984 (Box 3)
    - Outpatient Activity and Consultation, 1978-1980 (Box 3)
    - Personnel, 1977; 1982-1983; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Recruitment, 1975-1985; 11 folders
      - 1975-1976 (Box 3)
      - 1976-1977 (Box 3)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 3)
      - 1978 (Box 3)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 3)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 16)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 16)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 16)
      - 1982-1983 (Box 16)
      - 1983-1984 (Box 16)
      - Recruitment (Candidate) (Box 16)
  - Faculty Diagnostic Unit, 1976-1982; 5 folders (Box 3)
  - Financial Report, 1976-1979; 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Fellow Funding, 1977-1978 (Box 3)
  - Fellows, 1976 (Box 16)
  - Gastroenterology Division, 1975-1986
    - General, 1975-1983; 7 folders (Box 3)
    - Budgetary Matters, 1980 (Box 3)
    - Fellows, 1979 (Box 3)
    - Gastrointestinal Physiology Laboratory, 1983 (Box 3)
    - Michigan Gastrointestinal Peptide Research Center Grant, 1985-1986 (Box 4)
    - Patients, 1976-1977 (Box 16)
      [PR RESTRICTED until July 1 2077 ]
    - Personnel, 1977; 1983-1984; 2 folders (Box 16)
    - Recruiting, 1975-1984; 10 folders
      - 1976-1977 (Box 16)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 16)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 17)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 17)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 17)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 17)
      - 1982-1983 (Box 17)
      - 1983-1984 (Box 17)
    - Retrogade Cannulation, 1975-1976 (Box 4)
  - General Medicine Division, 1975-1987
    - General, 1975-1983; 7 folders (Box 4)
    - Medicine Walk-In Clinic, 1980-1982; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Outpatient Activity and Consultations, 1981-1982 (Box 4)
    - Personnel, 1982-1983 (Box 4)
    - Planning Committee, 1981-1982 (Box 4)
    - Recruiting, 1982-1987; 10 folders
      - 1981-1982 (Box 17)
      - 1982-1983 (Box 17)
      - 1986-1987 (Box 17)
        [PR RESTRICTED until July 1 2017 ]
    - Recruiting (Candidates), 6 folders (Box 17)
  - Geriatrics Division, 1975-1986
    - General, 1976-1984; 6 folders (Box 4)
    - Arthritis Program, 1975-1979; 4 folders (Box 4)
    - Development Funds (Allotments and Expenditures), 1979-1982; 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Division Proposal, 1977-1982; 5 folders (Box 4)
    - Fellows, 1980-1984; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Personnel, 1978-1982 (Box 17)
    - Recruiting, 1980-1986; 9 folders
      - 1980-1981 (Box 17)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 17)
      - 1982-1983 (Box 17)
      - 1983-1984 (Box 17)
      - 1984-1986 (Box 17)
        [PR RESTRICTED until July 1 2016 ]
    - Recruiting (Candidates), 4 folders (Box 17)
    - Research Program on the Biology of the Aging, 1979-1980 (Box 4)
    - Turner Building Programs, 1982-1984; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Turner Geriatric Center, 1983 (Box 4)
  - Hematology/Oncology Division, 1924-1985
    - General, 1971-1984; 11 folders
      - 1971-1984, 10 folders (Box 17)
      - 1971-1984, 1 folders
    - Division Chief Search, 1983 (Box 17)
    - Fellows, 1982-1983 (Box 5)
    - Grievances, 1977 (Box 17)
      [CR RESTRICTED until July 1 2077 ]
    - Human Use, 1978 (Box 17)
      [CR RESTRICTED until July 1 2078 ]
    - Personnel, 1977-1981; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Recruiting, 1973-1985; 16 folders
      - 1973-1974 (Box 18)
      - 1974 (Box 18)
      - 1975-1976 (Box 18)
      - 1976-1977 (Box 18)
      - 1977 (Box 18)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 18)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 18)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 18)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 18)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 18)
      - 1982-1983 (Box 18)
      - 1983-1984 (Box 18)
      - 1984 (Box 18)
      - 1984-1985 (Box 18)
      - 1985 (Box 18)
    - Recruiting (Candidates) (Box 18)
    - Simpson Memorial Institute, 1924 (Box 5)
  - Henry Ford Hospital, 1975-1981
    - General, 1975-1981; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Chief Internal Medicine--Search, 1977-1979 (Box 18)
  - Geriatrics Division, 1975-1986 (Box 5)
  - Hypertension Division, 1975-1983
    - General, 1975-1982; 3 folders (Box 5)
    - Hyperlipidemia Laboratory, 1983 (Box 18)
    - Recruiting, 1976-1982; 5 folders
      - 1976-1977 (Box 18)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 18)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 18)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 18)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 18)
  - Infectious Diseases Division, 1975-1984
    - General, 1975-1983; 7 folders (Box 5)
    - Budgetary Matters, 1975 (Box 18)
    - Personnel, 1983-1984 (Box 5)
    - Recruiting, 1975-1984; 6 folders
      - 1975-1976 (Box 18)
      - 1976-1977 (Box 18)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 18)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 18)
      - 1982-1983 (Box 18)
      - 1983-1984 (Box 18)
    - Space Inventory: Needs and Renovation, 1983-1984 (Box 5)
  - Internal Medicine Division, 1975-1982
    - Associates--Three-Year Evaluation, 1977-1980 (Box 5)
    - External Review, 1983 (Box 5)
    - Internal Review, 1975-1982; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Medical Service Plan, 1977-1980
    - General, 1977-1980 (Box 5)
    - Office Budget, D. Bachrach, 1978-1979 (Box 5)
  - Molecular Genetics Division, 1975-1984
    - General, 1983-1984 (Box 5)
    - Gene Transfer Group, 1983-1984 (Box 5)
    - Personnel, 1983-1984 (Box 5)
    - Recruiting, 1975-1983; 7 folders
      - 1976-1977 (Box 18)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 18)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 18)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 18)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 18)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 18)
      - 1982-1983 (Box 18)
  - Nephrology Division, 1975-1984
    - Chronic Hemodialysis Program, 1975-1979; 3 folders (Box 5)
    - Personnel, 1981-1982 (Box 18)
    - Recruiting, 1975-1983; 8 folders
      - 1975-1976 (Box 18)
      - 1976-1977, 2 folders (Box 18)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 18)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 18)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 18)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 18)
      - 1982-1983 (Box 18)
  - Nuclear Medicine Division, 1970-1986
    - General, 1974-1982; 8 folders
      - 1974-1982, 6 folders (Box 5)
      - 1976-1977 (Box 18)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 18)
    - Division Chief Search, 1983-1984 (Box 18)
    - Personnel, 1970-1986; 4 folders
      - 1970-1976 (Box 18)
      - 1976-1977 (Box 18)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 18)
      - 1982-1983 (Box 18)
    - Positron Emission Tomography (PET) Project, 1977-1984; 7 folders (Box 5)
    - Proposal for Myocardial Imaging, 1977-1984; 6 folders (Box 6)
    - Recruitment, 1976-1986; 8 folders
      - 1976-1977 (Box 19)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 19)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 19)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 19)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 19)
      - 1982-1983 (Box 19)
      - 1983-1984 (Box 19)
      - 1985-1986 (Box 19)
    - Recruitment (Candidates) (Box 19)
    - Review, 1983 (Box 6)
  - Pollard Research Center, 1977-1980; 3 folders (Box 6)
    (see also Pollard Medical Research Institute series, box 15)
  - Primary Care, 1975-1982
    - General, 1978-1980; 2 folders
      - 1978-1979 (Box 19)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 19)
    - Personnel, 1980 (Box 19)
  - Primary Care (cont.), 1975-1982
    - Preceptual Program
      - 1975-1982, 3 folders (Box 6)
      - 1975-1976, 1 folders (Box 19)
    - Recruiting, 1976-1981; 4 folders (Box 19)
    - Space Inventory Needs and Renovation, 1981-1982 (Box 6)
  - Pulmonary Division, 1977-1982
    - General
      - 1980-1981 (Box 6)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 19)
    - Equipment, 1979-1981 (Box 6)
    - Function Lab, 1977-1981 (Box 19)
      - 1977-1981, 3 folders
      - 1978-1979, 1 folders
    - Recruiting, 1976-1982; 6 folders
      - 1976-1977 (Box 19)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 19)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 19)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 19)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 19)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 19)
    - Respiratory Therapy, 1981-1982 (Box 6)
    - Satellite Blood Gas Lab, 1979-1981 (Box 6)
    - Wayne County Health Department (WCHD) Contract, 1978-1979 (Box 19)
  - Questionnaires, 1975-1982; 6 folders (Box 6)
  - Rackham Arthritis Research Unit Central Tissue Culture Facility, 1975-1976 (Box 6)
  - Retirement Furlough, 1977-1978 (Box 6)
  - Rheumatology Division, 1974-1987
    - General, 1975-1982; 7 folders (Box 6)
    - "Analysis and Simulation of the Wednesday Afternoon Arthritis Clinic at the University Hospital"--Technical Report No. 10, 1975 (Box 6)
    - Arthritis Center Grant, 1977-1982; 4 folders (Box 6)
    - Development Funds (allotments and expenditures), 1979-1981 (Box 6)
    - Division Chief Search, 1986-1987; 5 folders (Box 19)
    - Grievances, 1974 (Box 19)
    - Recruiting, 1976-1982; 5 folders
      - 1976-1977 (Box 19)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 19)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 19)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 19)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 19)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 19)
  - Robinson, (Wm. D.) Fund, 1978-1979 (Box 6)
  - Sabbatical Leaves, 1976-1982; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - St. Joseph Mercy Hospital, 1975-1982; 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Society Memberships, 1977-1978; 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Strengths Report, 1974 (Box 6)
  - Sturgis File, 1974-1981 (Box 6)
  - Tertiary, 1977-1978 (Box 6)
  - Turner Building Programs, 1975-1982; 6 folders (Box 7)
  - Veterans Administration Hospital, Cardiology Program, 1978-1980; 1980 (Box 19)
- Topical Files, 1975-1986
  Topical Files (6.1 linear feet) are arranged alphabetically and document the department's relationship with the Medical School administration, other departments and university hospitals. Research projects and department administrative activities are also documented through correspondence, memos and planning papers. The researcher should note that the Division Files series sometimes contains topical files and the Topical Files series sometimes contains division files. The files have been kept in the order in which they were received from the department. When looking for materials related to a particular topic or division, the researcher should search both series.
  - Academic Press, 1976 (Box 7)
  - Administration Recruitment, 1976-1982; 3 folders
    - 1976 (Box 19)
    - 1977 (Box 19)
    - 1982 (Box 19)
  - Admitting Policies, 1978-1983; 4 folders (Box 7)
  - Administration, 1977-1982; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Adolescent Medicine, 1975-1983; 4 folders (Box 7)
  - Advances in Internal Medicine (conference), 1976-1984; 8 folders (Box 7)
  - Affirmative Action, 1976-1979
    - Availability Assessment, 1976 (Box 7)
    - Update, 1979; 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Agreements, 1982 (Box 8)
  - American Society for Clinical Investigation (ASCI), 1979-1983
    - General, 1979-1983; 3 folders (Box 8)
    - NIH Review, 1983 (Box 8)
  - American Clinical and Climatological Association, 1981-1982; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - American Rheumatology Association (ARA), 1983
    - General, 1983 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 8)
  - Anatomy, 1976-1978 (Box 19)
  - Anesthesiology, 1976-1978 (Box 8)
  - Association of Professors of Medicine, 1983 (Box 8)
  - Attending Physician Discharge Approval, 1982-1983; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Bed Utilization, 1982-1983; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Biological Chemistry, 1976-1982; 11 folders
    - 1976-1983, 3 folders (Box 8)
    - 1976 (Box 19)
    - 1977 (Box 19)
    - 1978 (Box 19)
    - 1979 (Box 19)
    - 1980 (Box 19)
    - 1981 (Box 19)
    - 1982 (Box 19)
    - 1983 (Box 19)
  - Biomedical Research Center, 1977-1983; 7 folders
    - 1977 (Box 8)
    - 1978 (Box 19)
    - 1979 (Box 8)
    - 1980 (Box 8)
    - 1981 (Box 8)
    - 1982 (Box 19)
    - 1983 (Box 19)
  - Burn Center, 1978 (Box 8)
  - Category I & II, 1976-1982
    - Faculty Diagnostic Unit, 1979-1982; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Research Track and Clinical Track, 1978-1982; 3 folders (Box 8)
    - Appendix A, 1976-1978, 1981-1982, 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Central Society for Clinical Research (CSCR), 1980-1983; 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Chelsea Medical Center, 1985-1986 (Box 8)
  - Clinical Pharmacology, 1975-1983
    - General, 1975-1983; 5 folders (Box 8)
    - Upjohn Center, 1977 (Box 8)
  - Clinical Priorities Committee, 1985-1986; 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Clinical Research Center (CRC), 1975-1984 (Box 9)
    - General, 1975-1984; 9 folders
      - 1975 (Box 19)
      - 1976 (Box 9)
      - 1977 (Box 9)
      - 1978 (Box 9)
      - 1979 (Box 9)
      - 1980 (Box 20)
      - 1981 (Box 9)
      - 1982 (Box 9)
      - 1983 (Box 9)
    - Annual Progress Report, 1979-1983; 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Site Visit, October 19-20, 1983 (Box 9)
  - Consultation Service, 1975-1978, 1981, 5 folders (Box 9)
  - Deans Advisory Council, 1983 (Box 9)
  - Dental School, 1976-1981 (Box 9)
  - Dermatology, 1976-1983; 4 folders (Box 9)
  - Development Fund Capital Campaign, 1977-1978 (Box 9)
  - Director's Advisory Committee, 1981-1984 (Box 9)
  - Division Chiefs, 1976 (Box 9)
  - Emergency Room, 1975-1983
    - General, 1975-1983; 8 folders
      - 1975-1983, 4 folders (Box 9)
      - 1975 (Box 20)
        [CR RESTRICTED until July 1 2050 ]
      - 1976-1977 (Box 20)
        [CR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2052 ]
      - 1979-1980 (Box 20)
        [CR RESTRICTED until July 1 2055 ]
      - 1982 (Box 20)
        [CR RESTRICTED until July 1 2057 ]
    - Proposal, 1978-1982 (Box 9)
  - Emergency Services, 1977-1978 (Box 20)
    [CR RESTRICTED until July 1 2053 ]
  - Employee Health Service, 1976-1981 (Box 9)
  - Family Practice975-1983
    - Internal Review (Box 9)
    - Program, 1975-1983; 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Progress Report and Planning Overview, 1978 (Box 10)
    - Proposal for a Required M-3 Family Practice Clerkship, 1982 (Box 10)
  - Grants Correspondence, 1981 (Box 10)
  - Henry Ford-UM Joint Committee on Affiliation, 1977-1983; 4 folders (Box 10)
  - Hospital Information Systems, 1979 (Box 10)
  - Hospital Planning, Areas of Excellence, 1978-1979 (Box 10)
  - Hospital Registration System, 1979 (Box 10)
  - Human Genetics, 1977-1984; 3 folders
    - 1977 (Box 19)
    - 1981 (Box 20)
    - 1982-1984 (Box 20)
  - Immunology, 1975-1977
    - General, 1975-1979; 2 folders (Box 20)
    - Inpatient Consultation Unit (, 1977 (Box 20)
  - Joint Commission on Accreditation of Hospitals, 1977-1983; 4 folders (Box 10)
  - Main Hospital Operating Team (MHOT), 1982 (Box 10)
  - Medicaid Task Force, 1983 (Box 10)
  - Medical/Dental Staff Meetings, 1982-1983 (Box 10)
  - Medical Records Department, 1975-1979; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Medical School Task Force, 1982-1983; 3 folders (Box 10)
  - Medical Science III--Planning, 1977-1978, 1981, 3 folders (Box 10)
  - Medical Scientist Training Program, 1983 (Box 10)
  - Medical Service Plan, 1977-1983 (Box 11)
    - General, 1977-1982; 4 folders (Box 11)
    - Internal Medicine Associates--Three Year Review, 1977-1980 (Box 11)
    - Manager's Coordinating Council, 1979-1983; 5 folders (Box 11)
    - Task Force, 1979 (Box 11)
    - Progress Report, 1982 (Box 11)
  - Michigan Kidney Registry Progress Report, 1976 (Box 11)
  - Michigan Medical Scientist Training Program, 1983 (Box 11)
  - Molecular Genetics Report to the Governor, 1982 (Box 11)
  - Neurology, 1976-1977; 1980-1982; 2 folders
    - 1976-1977 (Box 20)